Alan Barrett

Birkenhead, England, United Kingdom



azzabarrett1@gmail.com



07398594631



linkedin.com/in/alanbarrettdev

Summary

As a self-taught software developer, I possess a diverse skill set that includes expertise in Python, HTML, CSS, Git, Web Design/Front End Development principles and JavaScript. My passion for creating new projects and refining existing ones has enabled me to develop a keen eye for enhancing the user experience. I am dedicated to producing top-notch results, and my attention to detail is evident in every project I undertake.

When I am not coding, I enjoy indulging in my hobbies, such as gaming (with ARK Survival Evolved being my favourite game), following football (especially as a die-hard Liverpool fan!), and immersing myself in the world of Harry Potter through both the books and movies.

Experience



General Manager Operations

Drunken Lullabies

Feb 2021 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Helping to run and maintain a busy gaming server with over 1k members, building a website and discord bots for this cluster. Communication and leadership skills were essential in this role to help the server run smoothly and manage the tasks of the admin team in general.

Tech Stack:

- HTML
- CSS
- Python
- Mongo DB
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap

During my web development tasks in this role I have demonstrated excellent attention to detail and problem solving skills.



📆 Porter

ISS A/S

Aug 2019 - May 2021 (1 year 10 months)

During my time here, I was communicating with all the wards in the hospital to ensure they had all of the equipment, supplies and food that they needed to run a good service. Other duties included transporting used linen, waste management and cleaning (I would often take overtime on the Rapid Response cleaning team).



Sainsbury's

Sep 2018 - Jun 2020 (1 year 10 months)

During my time at Sainsburys I was helping customers in any way I could, from serving them at the checkouts, to helping them find groceries on the shelves. I was also responsible for keeping the shelves well stocked, communicating store needs to management, cleaning public areas and cleaning of the Costa machine!

Customer Service Representative

Sports Direct

Aug 2016 - Sep 2018 (2 years 2 months)

During my time here I worked on the footwear department where as well as customer service my duties included communicating with the stockroom team to get the correct size and style of footwear for my customers. I also had to sell KPIS such as insoles and socks to hit performance targets. Teamwork and communication were vital to ensuring the footwear department was run in a smooth manner and customers were helped efficiently and professionally.

Education



Sololearn

Certificate, Python

Nov 2021 - Mar 2022

I have gained certificates in Python, HTML, CSS, and PHP! To gain these certificates, I was required to show both a theoretical and practical knowledge of the stated programming languages by completing challenges based on the learning materials provided! I paid for the premium membership in order to further hone my skills with extra challenges!

🚅 Wirral Metropolitan College - Wirral Met College

Sports Science Level 3 Extended Diploma, Sports and Exercise Sep 2016 - Jun 2018

Licenses & Certifications



🌀 CSS - Sololearn



🌀 HTML - Sololearn

Skills

Sales • Discord API • Customer Relationship Management (CRM) • Customer Service • Teamwork • MongoDB • JavaScript • Communication • HTML5 • css 3